<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Kaylee Barrera</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Kaylee Barrera</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.139.3</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>About Me</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a broad interest in exoplanets, with a focus on studying young planets to better understand planetary evolution and planet demographics. My current work involves cross-validating Gaussian process models of stellar activity in radial velocity measurements. I am also enthusiastic about exploring other exoplanet detection and characterization techniques, as well as learning about the development of more precise instrumentation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Beyond research at MIT, I serve as President of the Earth, Atmospheric, and Planetary Science (EAPS) Undergraduate Council, where I have been fostering our growing undergrad community and contributing to the improvement of the undergraduate curriculum. I also hold a position as Co-President of &lt;a href=&#34;https://sites.mit.edu/uwip/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;MIT&amp;rsquo;s chapter of Undergraduate Women in Physics&lt;/a&gt; to support gender minorities in physics and help promote civic engagement on campus through &lt;a href=&#34;https://mitvote.mit.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;MITvote&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;span-stylecolor1d4dadcurrent-projectspan-span-stylefont-family-courier-neweurydicespan-and-the-hd-63433-system&#34;&gt;&lt;span style=&#34;color:#1d4dad&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Current Project:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span style=&#34;font-family: Courier New&#34;&gt;eurydice&lt;/span&gt; and the HD 63433 system&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img loading=&#34;lazy&#34; src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/eurydicedemo.png&#34; alt=&#34;img&#34;  /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;High stellar activity from young, active stars is a major obstacle when using the radial velocity method to detect exoplanets, limiting our ability to study young exoplanets&amp;rsquo; properties and evolution. An increasingly common approach to modeling stellar noise in radial velocity measurements is Gaussian Process regression. However, there is no standardized method for assessing the predictiveness of these stellar activity models in the exoplanet community, a problem that has led to overfitting and unreliable results in the past (see &lt;a href=&#34;https://iopscience.iop.org/article/10.3847/1538-3881/acde78&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Blunt et al. 2023&lt;/a&gt;). As the search for exoplanets begins to focus on younger and more active stars, it is becoming increasingly important to understand the extent of overfitting on stellar activity models.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
